<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="E3DModelInstanceManager" inherits="Object" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		Global manager for tracking and updating active E3DModelInstance nodes.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		[E3DModelInstanceManager] acts as a registry for all [E3DModelInstance] nodes currently active in the scene. It provides centralized control for batch operations, such as reloading all active models when global settings (like texture quality or game directory) change. The registry tracks instance identities defensively so stale nodes left behind by scene teardown or hot reload are ignored instead of being dereferenced, and it can force a global teardown of live E3D renderer state before the extension library is unloaded.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="register_instance">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="instance" type="E3DModelInstance" />
			<description>
				Registers an [E3DModelInstance] with the manager. This is typically called automatically when a model instance enters the scene tree.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="reload_all">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Triggers a reload for all currently registered [E3DModelInstance] nodes. Useful for updating the visual representation of all models simultaneously.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="reload_instance">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="instance" type="E3DModelInstance" />
			<description>
				Forces a specific [E3DModelInstance] to re-instantiate its geometry and re-apply its materials from the [E3DModel] resource.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="teardown_all_for_extension_reload">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Forces every currently registered [E3DModelInstance] to release generated child nodes, optimized renderer instances, and pending reload state before the GDExtension library is reloaded.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="unregister_instance">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="instance" type="E3DModelInstance" />
			<description>
				Removes an [E3DModelInstance] from the manager's registry. This is typically called automatically when a model instance leaves the scene tree.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
	<signals>
		<signal name="instances_reloaded">
			<param index="0" name="instance" type="Object" />
			<description>
				Emitted when a model instance has been successfully reloaded and its node hierarchy has been updated.
			</description>
		</signal>
	</signals>
</class>
