<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="ResourceCache" inherits="RefCounted" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		Global singleton for memory and persistent disk caching of resources.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		[ResourceCache] provides a centralized, thread-safe system for caching resources used by the MaSzyna API Wrapper. It maintains an in-memory dictionary for fast access and a persistent disk cache in [code]user://cache/[/code] for long-term storage. Resources are identified by their original source paths and organized into subdirectories based on their type. Disk cache files are stored as Godot-native [code].res[/code] files with MD5-hashed filenames to ensure cross-platform compatibility and avoid path length issues.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="clear">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Clears both the memory cache and the persistent disk cache for the specified subdirectory.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="Resource" />
			<param index="0" name="path" type="String" />
			<description>
				Attempts to retrieve a resource from the cache. It first checks the memory cache, and if not found, attempts to load it from the persistent disk cache. Returns an invalid [Ref] if the resource is not cached.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="has" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="bool" />
			<param index="0" name="path" type="String" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the resource exists in either the memory cache or the persistent disk cache.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="remove" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="path" type="String" />
			<description>
				Removes the specified resource from both the memory cache and the persistent disk cache.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="path" type="String" />
			<param index="1" name="resource" type="Resource" />
			<description>
				Stores the given resource in the memory cache and serializes it to the persistent disk cache in the specified subdirectory.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
